

MACHINE LEARNING RESEARCHER • DATA SCIENTIST

🖾 ekohgenius@gmail.com . 🖸 coekoh . Oekohgenius . 🗖 courage-ekoh

Synopsis.

Data Science professional with experience working in the energy industry and fintech. Possess the unique ability to utilize data insight for business cases to mitigate risk and improve business output. Proficient in various programming languages as well as building ML models from scratch and with existing libraries. Comfortable with statistical and data analysis, mathematics, research, and some aspects of financial modelling.

Education_

Carnegie Mellon University

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

MS, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

- Concentration: Applied Machine Learning
- CQPA: 3.68/4.0

University of Ibadan

Jun 2014 - May 2019

BSc, INDUSTRIAL AND PRODUCTION ENGINEERING

- Class Rank: 5/34
- CGPA: 5.7/7.0

Professional Experience

Carnegie Mellon University

Jan 2022 - Present

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT (Part-Time)

TA for the graduate level course 18-661 <u>Introduction to Machine Learning for Engineers</u>

- Conduct recitations to help over 100 students grasp some of the difficult concepts taught in class with example problems (both theoretical and coding solutions)
- · Hold office hours to respond to students' questions with regards to the assignments or concepts taught in class
- Grading and providing feedback to students on assignments, guizzes, and projects
- Prepare homework problems

Koa Technology, Nairobi, Kenya (Fintech Start-up)

Sen 2021 - Jan 202

DATA SCIENTIST

- · Work with the operations team to provide insight from the data produced by all departments and foster growth in the company
- · Maintain and update back-end queries to constantly meet business needs in terms of the data pulled out
- Created over 90% of the data engineering processes as well as the various reporting and visualizations used by the various departments in the daily running of the company

TFE Energy, Cape-Town South Africa

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

MACHINE LEARNING CONSUTANT

- Utilized Machine learning to build a yield prediction algorithm for mini-grid connections in rural Africa
- · Evaluated the possibility of data-backed refinancing for mini-grid connections by combining clustering, and classification algorithms
- Worked extensively with geospatial data to understand how development affects electricity access and consumption in rural villages.

Koa Technology, Nairobi, Kenya (Fintech Start-up)

May 2021 - Sep 2021

BI DEVELOPER & DATA ANALYST (Internship)

- Conducted statistical and data analysis with captured data and provide business intelligence to aid decision processes for the Operations, Marketing and Tech departments.
- Achieved 2,650% increase in active savers within 3-months from launch by pioneering data-driven initiatives on customer acquisition and retention.
- Built tools from ground-up that provided 100% visibility into KPIs across the entire company

Schlumberger Oilfield Services, Port-Harcourt, Nigeria

Aug 2017 - Feb 2018

WELL SERVICES MAINTENANCE ENGINEER (Internship)

- Deployed GPS trackers and Maintenance Information Systems on over 200 oilfield assets (covering about 60% of the project, within a month) for better asset and maintenance management as part of the Global Traceability Project
- Maintained and certified pressure control equipment such as treating lines and valves to provide up to 99.99% availability on the field
- Conducted routine maintenance on oilfield equipment, i.e., pumps, engines, mixers, etc. that ensured downtime was near 0 hours.

Recent Project .

Extreme Multi-Domain, Multi-Task Learning With Unified Text-to-Text Transfer Transformers

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

- Built an Al agent that performs multi-domain task with a single model. Our model does code generation from docstring, code summarization, chess move prediction, and chess game evaluation.
- Supervisor: Prof. Bhiksha Raj and Prof. Rita Singh

Other Projects

- Face Recognition and Face detection with Convolution Neural Networks (ResNet-34)
- Speech Recognition with Recurrent Neural Networks (LSTMs)
- Detection of Malicious URLs using K-Nearest Neighbour Classifier

Skills

Machine Learning Sci-Kit Learn, Ensembles (Random Forest, XGBoost), ANN, CNN, RNN, Classification (Decision Tree, KNN,

Logistic Regression, SVM), Clustering (k-means, k-means++, GMM), Pytorch, hugging-faceLinear Algebra,

Statistics, Calculus

Data Science NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Tableau, Metabase, SQL, A/B Testing, StatsModel, SciPy, MS EXCEL, Google Data

Studio

Programming/Frameworks

Software

AutoCAD, Inventor, MS Office Suite, SAP, Salesforce, Unity

Coursework Applied Stochastic Processes, Mathematics for Machine Learning, Data Inference and Applied Machine

Python (Intermediate), Java (Intermediate), LINUX (Beginner), C/C++ (Beginner), AWS

Learning, Introduction to Machine Learning for Engineers, Augmented and Virtual Reality, Data Structures and

Algorithm, Introduction to Information Security, Introduction to Deep Learning

Other Courses

Deep Learning Specialization (deeplearning.ai on Coursera)

Present

Machine Learning for Production Specialization (MLOps) (deeplearning.ai on Coursera)

Present

Data Analysis with Python (IBM on Coursera)

Oct 2019

Data Foundations (Business Analytics) Nanodegree (Udacity)

Oct 2018

Activities_

Students' Guild, Carnegie Mellon University Africa

Feb 2021 - Dec 202

PRESIDENT (First International student to attain this position)

- Introduced the peer-mentoring scheme among students where students can get help from other students on programming and maths skills through weekly organized tutorials. More than 60 students benefit from this scheme on a Week-on-week basis
- Negotiated the set-up of a trust-fund for students having financial challenges, with the Carnegie Mellon University Africa Alumni Association
- Managed other ministers and coordinated the smooth running of students' activities
- Represented students in all organs of the university administration

Toastmasters International

Feb 2021 - Dec 202

MEMBER, Kigali, Rwanda

- Practised on the presentation mastery path
- Delivered speech fortnightly to improve my public speaking skills

Unilever Nigeria Plc

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

CAMPUS BRAND AMBASSADOR, University of Ibadan

- Championed a massive publicity campaign for Unilever Africa Idea Trophy (UAIT 2016); received commendation for the highest institution entry in the country
- Organized a mentoring session for the University of Ibadan UAIT 2016 teams; A teams from University of Ibadan placed first position in Nigeria
- Took responsibility for all on campus employer (Unilever) branding activities (both online and offline)

Industrial Engineering Students Association, University of Ibadan

Feb 2016 - Dec 2016

PUBLIC RELATIONS OFFICER

- Reinstated the press organization of the association
- Pioneered the celebration of members on their special days
- Was in-charge of the association's PR

Awards

•	CIT Dean's Fellowship, Carnegie Mellon University's College of Engineering	2020
•	National Finalist (Nigeria), Global Management Challenge	2019
•	National Merit Scholarship, Total Exploration and Production Company	2016
•	Undergraduate Scholarship, Agbami Medical and Engineering Professionals	2016
•	Undergraduate Scholarship, Midwestern Oil and Gas Company	2016
•	Post-Primary Scholarship, Shell Production Development Company	2007

anuary 2022 Courage Fkoh